Anu Shankar S D

Front End Developer with a keen eye for detail

Profile

Seasoned and independent Front End Developer with 5 years of experience in blending the art of design with the skill of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website development, feature optimization, and relentless debugging and also have hands-on experience in Angular /React + Redux

Very keen on aesthetics and UI design.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer - QBurst Technologies, Trivandrum

April 2018 - currently employed

- Designed browser-compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript.
- Built single-page applications (SPA) using React and Angular, responsive web design, UI using HTML5, CSS3 media queries where its an expression and can be used to either true or false.
- Developed social media, e-commerce, and hospitality and also done White labeling of an existing site.web applications using React js.
- Modularize/optimize components in the angular codebase that have been ported over from legacy codebase whenever a scope is identified.
- Migrate the existing angular-webpack app into angular-CLI for better performance and resolve lazy loading issues.
- Constant code reviews, and review of peer work, and done code optimization, quality, and reliable developer testing with a proper report.
- Have commendable knowledge of ES6 and typescript so switching between JS framework and library becomes easier.
- Coordinated with other engineers to evaluate and improve software interfaces
- Developed screens with Charts, GoogleMaps, and many more as per visualization requirements.
- Building stable and maintainable codebase using React and Angular and followed Agile methodology.
- Working directly with client stakeholders to develop technical solutions for the business cases

Software Engineer - Triassic solutions private limited, Trivandrum

Sep 2017 - April 2018

• Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible, and accessibility compliant websites, achieving 19% faster load time than the industry average

Personal Information

+917598106427 anushankar.work@gmail.com

Professional skills

Front End framework and Library (Angular, React)

JavaScript, Typescript, ES6

HTML, CSS

Responsive UI Design

Google Maps API, CSS3 FlexBox

Glt,Webpack

Project Management

Jira

Slack

Redmine

Languages

English

Malayalam

Tamil

Experience

- Produced stunning visual elements of web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code while producing high quality, reusable markup using HTML5 and CSS3
- Designing frontend within object-oriented Javascript frameworks like Angular

Web Developer - Tinggal, Trivandrum

April 2017 - Sep 2017

- Implement scenarios based on requirements.
- Developed the hotel admin module.
- · Created the entire UI for the website.
- Integrated backend API to the front-end application
- Developer testing and peer-to-peer code reviews have been done.
- Worked for the product which is a online marketplace that allows users to find quality hotels that allow users to find quality hotels across Asia

Web Developer - Limeseed Innovations, Bangalore

July 2016 - April 2017

- · Carried out day-day-day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Developed and implemented performance improvement strategies and plans to promote continuous improvement.
- Junior Web developer able to build a Web presence from the ground up -- from concept, navigation, layout, and programming to UX
- Co-developed a secure Web site from scratch. Launched visually appealing, user-friendly Webscape with interactive features to optimize traffic, page views, the site "stickiness" and user experience

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science and Engineering) - Anna University, Chennai

jun 2011 - April 2015

• Graduated with a 68.3 %

References

Anusree M Nambiar - Front-end Engineering consultant

anu.sripuri@gmail.com - https://www.linkedin.com/in/anusreemn/